markettraders.com 2016-11-19

# Privacy Policy | Market Traders Institute

Effective Date: 12/11/2014

This website is owned and operated by Market Traders Institute Inc. You can reach us by phone at 800-866-7431 or email at [compliance[@]markettraders.com.](mailto:compliance@markettraders.com) Our address is 3900 Millenia Blvd. Orlando, FL. 32839

**Our Commitment to Privacy**

Your privacy is important to Market Traders Institute, Inc. (MTI). To reinforce our commitment to protect your privacy, we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. This policy summarizes the information, including personally identifiable information, that we collect through our website and how that information may be used. By using our website you consent to the collection and use of this information.

We reserve the right to change our privacy policy at any time. In the event we make changes to any of the terms or conditions of this privacy policy, we will incorporate those changes into this document so you will know what information is being collected and how that information is being used. We will undertake best efforts to notify you of any changes to this privacy policy utilizing the last email address you have provided to us; however, it is your responsibility to keep your email address current and to monitor this policy for any changes. Continued use of this website and/or our services shall constitute consent to this policy and any changes made hereto.

**Information We Collect**

We may collect and use your IP address to help administer services on our website as well as to improve your user experience. We do not use your IP address to collect any personally identifiable information. Demographic and interest data is also collected at our Website. We use this data to tailor the information emailed to our customers and to display the content according to their preferences.  
We offer a variety of both free and paid services and products that will require your voluntary submission of information. The information that may be collected is as follows:

  * **Full Name**
  * **Address, including street name, city/town, state and zip code**
  * **Email Address**
  * **Phone Number**
  * **Country**
  * **IP Address**
  * **Payment Information**

If you are purchasing products, we may use a third party provider such as a shopping cart to collect a credit card number and related payment information or alternative methods of payment. If you provide information on third party sites, the privacy policy and terms of service on those sites are applicable.

We may also collect information you provide about others, such as how you were referred to our website and programs.

**How We Use Information**  
Market Traders Institute, Inc may use the information that you provide through our site in order to market our products and services as well as products and services from select third parties. Our goal is to utilize the information collected to ensure a positive experience with our company and website, as well as to help us understand what we can do to better serve you. We will also use this information to contact you when necessary.

**IF YOU NO LONGER WISH TO RECEIVE EMAILS FROM MARKET TRADERS INSTITUTE, INC. PLEASE CLICK THE UNSUBSCRIBE LINK INCLUDED IN OUR EMAILS OR CONTACT US DIRECTLY AT[COMPLIANCE [@] MARKETTRADERS.com.](mailto:compliance@markettraders.com)**

**IF YOU PROVIDE YOUR TELEPHONE NUMBER, YOU AGREE AND ACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOU MAY RECEIVE TELEPHONE CALLS FROM US WITH INFORMATION REGARDING NEW PRODUCTS AND SERVICES, OR UPCOMING EVENTS. IF YOU DO NOT WISH TO RECEIVE CALLS FROM IN THE FUTURE, PLEASE LET US KNOW IMMEDIATELY BY EMAILING US AT[COMPLIANCE [@] MARKETTRADERS.COM](mailto:compliance@markettraders.com) OR CALLING US AT [(407) 740-0900](tel:14077400900).**

**Sharing Information**  
Privacy matters are very important to us and all available resources and processes are implemented to make sure your information remains safe and secure. We do not sell, license, lease or otherwise disclose your personal information to any third party for any reason except as noted herein.

We may share personal information described above with our affiliates for business purposes, such as, but not limited to, servicing customers and informing customers about new products and services, and as permitted by applicable law. Our affiliates may include companies controlled or owned by Market Traders Institute, Inc. as well as companies that have an ownership interest in our company. The information we share with affiliates may include any of the information described above, such as your name, address and email address. Our affiliates maintain the privacy of your information to the same extent MTI does in accordance with this Policy.

Information may be shared with third parties that perform support services for Market Traders Institute, Inc. such as non-affiliate companies that provide professional, legal, or accounting advice. Non-affiliated companies that assist us in providing services to you are required to maintain the confidentiality of such information to the extent they receive it and to use your personal information only in the course of providing such services, as directed by MTI. We may also disclose information in response to legal requests, such as a court order or subpoena.

As we develop our business, we might sell, buy, restructure or reorganize our business or assets. In the event of a merger, consolidation, sale, liquidation or transfer of assets, MTI may, in its sole and absolute discretion, transfer, sell or assign information collected, including without limitation, non-personal information and personal information, to one or more affiliated or unaffiliated third parties.

**Public Forums**  
This site may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

**Our Commitment to Security and Confidentiality**  
This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. The transfer of personal information is communicated via state-of-the-art encryption. Our secure Website server and database reside behind a firewall in a secure datacenter with fault tolerance and fire protection.

Notwithstanding our commitment to security and confidentiality, the fact remains that no transmission over the internet or any wireless network provides complete security. In light of the inherent vulnerability, you acknowledge that: (a) there exists security and privacy limitations which are beyond our control; (b) there can be no guaranty of the security, integrity and privacy limitations related to information transmitted to us over the internet or through our website; and/or (c) outside interference through piracy cannot be controlled by us and as such, information and data transmitted may be viewed by unauthorized third parties.

**Cookies**  
We use cookie technology to help members move faster through the site and to keep track of your shopping cart. We also use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests. A cookie is a small file sent to your computer by our site server. The most commonly employed cookies on our site server are those that help us establish (1) whether you are a registered member of our site, and (2) whether a registered member has opted to use the “auto-login” feature, which eliminates the requirement for registered members to identify themselves each time they visit our site. A separate cookie from the company that handles our advertising production and tracking system helps identify which ad you may be clicking on, so that you will be linked to the correct site. We may also use cookie technology to track the site’s aggregate page views, which helps us determine which features the user base seems to be most or least interested in. Please note that cookies cannot get information from your hard drive against your will, cannot destroy files, and cannot send you viruses.

Each time your visit our website our servers automatically record your activity and information such as your IP address and/or the domain from which you are visiting. We also record which links on our webpage you click on or visit and any search terms you use. We use this data for website maintenance and technical administration. Your IP address is never linked with any personally identifiable information to identify you personally, except in the case of our investigation into a violation of the terms of use or alleged misconduct.

**Links to Other Websites**  
This site may contain links to third parties’ websites. Please note that we are not responsible for the collection, use, maintenance, sharing, or disclosure of data and information by such third parties. If you provide information on third party sites, the privacy policy and terms of service on those sites are applicable. Especially if the third party site is used in connection with a purchase of a product. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of websites that you visit before submitting personal information.

**Our Commitment to Children’s Privacy**  
Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we do not collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under the age of thirteen (13).

**Opt-Out**  
If you do not wish to have your personal information disclosed to our affiliates, third parties or to be used by Market Traders Institute, Inc. as described in this Policy please contact us via e-mail at: [compliance [@] markettraders.com.](mailto:compliance@markettraders.com)

Or send a written request to:

Market Traders Institute Attn: Compliance 3900 Millenia Blvd Orlando, FL 32839

**How to Contact Us**  
Should you have any other questions or concerns about this privacy policy, please call us at 800-866-7431 or send us an email at [compliance [@] markettraders.com.](mailto:compliance@markettraders.com)
